KANISHK BADOLA

+91-9045077585 | KANISHKBADOLA5@GMAIL.COM

OBJECTIVE

Software engineer having 3.1 years experience and working as a Senior Software developer (Angular8) with TypeScript, consuming RESTFUL web services and using Karma and Jasmine testing framework in AGILE methodology. Strong engineering professional with a bachelor's degree in Computer science and technology from Graphic Era University, Dehradun.

CORE COMPETENCIES

COMPUTER LANGUAGES	PROFICIENT TypeScript Python Angular 8 Jasmine/Karma HTML5 CSS3 Core JAVA Selenium	FAMILIAR WITH RESTFUL API Node.js	SOFTWARE KNOWN GIT/GITLAB BITBUCKET Jenkins GITLAB JAWS/NVDA HP-LeanFt	WORKING METHODOLOGIES • AGILE/SCRUM • FLAT HEIRARCHY
IDE	WebstormPyCharmVSCodeEclipseTurbo C		OPERATING SYSTEMS KNOWN	Windows NT (Win 98 and above)Linux

EDUCATION

DEGREE	INSTITUTION	PERCENTAGE/CGPA
Bachelor of Technology - Computer Science and Engineering	Graphic Era University, Dehradun	72%
HSC	Adarsh Bal Niketan, Roorkee	88%
SSLC	Adarsh Bal Niketan, Roorkee	82%

WORK EXPERIENCE

- Trainee at Mphasis training center in Mangalore from 3rd March 2017 till 3rd September 2017.
- Worked as a Automation Test Engineer in FedEx CDG2020 project from 4th September 2017 1st May 2018 at Mphasis.
- Worked as a Front end web developer at FedEx.com offshore team(client of Mphasis) from 2nd May 2018 till 13th September at Mphasis.
- Working as a Senior developer at Solvay offshore team(client of Mu-Sigma) from 4th November 2018 till now at Mu-Sigma.

Project - 1 (4th September 2017 - 1st May 2018):

Name & Client: CDG2020, EU client - FedEx.

Description: CDG2020 is a multi-year program to increase the sort capacity of the CDG hub, involving Implementation of a new automated sort facility within the hub, simultaneous utilization of the existing sort facility (manual) with the new automated facility,

Modernization/Retiring of legacy CDG systems and Implementation of Hubstack applications (Saber & GSS) that have been built on FedEx standard technologies

Role: Automation Test Engineer.

Responsibilities: Creating automated scripts by using HP-LeanFt, manual test cases and test scenarios for FedEx CDG2020 project.

<u>Project - 2 (2nd May 2018 - 13th September 2018):</u>

Name & Client: MAGIC, US client -FedEx.

Description: MAGIC project uses latest Angular version along with AEM concept to make the FedEx application more efficient and user friendly. It covers unit testing as well by checking the code coverage through SonarQube which ensures that coding standards are met Automation testing carried on using selenium by implementing JAVA. Several more testing included as a part of DOD.

Role: Angular Developer

Responsibilities:

- Following Agile Methodology and participating in all the scrum ceremonies.
- Following a proper coding standard.
- Writing unit test cases for the corresponding developed code.
- Taking care of all the functional and NFRs including ADA.
- Getting the code reviewed through the architects.
- Checking the code coverage by running the SonarQube tool.
- Building the project using Jenkins and deploying it to the test levels.
- Creating Automation scripts using selenium & java.
- Upgrading the angular version and updating the code across all the application.
- Interacting with clients and architects for problem solving sessions.
- Giving demo of the project to the clients during their visit and floor walk.

Project - 3 (13th September 2018 - Present):

Client Description: A global leader in advanced materials and specialty chemicals with forte in materials and innovation helping to design everyday solutions in clean mobility and resource efficiency.

Role: Senior Software Developer.

Responsibilities:

- Building and setting up framework for web apps in different projects across account
- Performing code review for peers, maintaining code quality throughout the app.
- Writing unit test cases for the corresponding developed code.
- Deploying web apps on Google Cloud Platform using Git automation pipeline.
- Automated dynamic generated monthly organizational report using Python.

TRAINING

- Developed automated scripts by using Selenium Webdriver for automation testing of Online Car Rental website in Cucumber and TestNG framework.
- Developed manual test cases and test scenarios for Online Car Rental website
- Developed Online House Rental Website using JSP (front end & back end)
- Developed Online food joint venture (front end) by using HTML5 and CSS3

CERTIFICATIONS

- J2EE website development certificate by SyncIT
- PHP website development certificate by SyncIT

NOTABLE ACHIEVEMENTS

- Acquired Summit award for creating Communication Dashboard using Angular 5 for MAGIC project.
- Received several appreciation letters from Product Owner and Mangers fordedicated performances.
- Acquired II position in ROBO SOCCER at GRAFEST 2014, annual technical fest of Graphic Era University.
- Worked as a permanent member in AIESEC(2013-2014)
- Received scholarship in Senior Secondary and Secondary School examination and in Graphic Era University as well.

LANGUAGES KNOWN

- English Full professional proficiency.
- Hindi Full working proficiency.

HOBBIES

- Playing guitar.
- Cooking.